Tyler Hirn

■ tylerrhirn@gmail.com □ 9565782025 🛅 in/tylerhirn 🛥 tylerhirn.dev

SUMMARY

My expertise includes project design and direction, data integration and interpretation, and user understanding. My expertise includes project design and direction, data integration and interpretation, and user understanding. I enjoy designing new ideas and novel solutions to challenging problems. Check out my website at tylerhirn.dev.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Software Engineering & Bachelor of Psychology

Auburn University · Auburn, AL · 2023 · 3.77

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer

Campus Web Solutions

January 2021 - August 2022, Auburn, AL

- · Developed and maintained several applications utilizing a variety of technologies, including .NET, Javascript, CSS, and SQL in an Agile environment.
- Streamlined ticket logistics for the entirety of Auburn facility staff by developing a custom web application that processed over \$100,000 dollars worth in football ticketing every season.
- · Developed an election web application for the election process of Auburn University's Board of Directors with a team of 4 developers under 1 month, resulting in an efficient election process.
- · Collaborated closely on Auburn's pharmacy scheduler, COVID vaccine plan, and Auburn facility staff healthcare scheduling software.
- · Implemented a student elections logistics display in an ASP.NET Core MVC application, personally approved by Gov. Ivey, that conveyed concurrent election progress and status for over 30,000 voters.

Elected Director of Housing Operations

The Delta Chi Fraternity at Auburn University

January 2019 - January 2021, Auburn, AL

- · As a Director of Housing Operations, reduced the time required to assign 50 chores weekly from 1 hour to 5 minutes by creating a chore schedule generator.
- \cdot Reduced overall costs by 20% by implementing scheduled supply deliveries and bulk orders.

PROJECTS

Core App

Personal Project · May 2022 - Present

- · Designed and Engineering wellness app using machine learning, Flutter and statistical analysis to assist in self discovery and track mood changes throughout the week
- · This application incorporated technologies like firebase db, Flutter, Python, Pandas, Numpy, statistics, and custom built SVC machine learning models.
- · As a result, the app was able to achieve an accuracy of 80% in determining user moods while providing statistically relevant information on the contributing factors of their moods, all while remaining a relevant and engaging product.

INVOLVEMENT

Research Assistant

Auburn University · Department of Psychology · January 2023 - Present

- · Administered a study through a chatbot to test the accuracy of a Natural Language Processor model that determines if patients are being deceptive.
- · Analyze and draw conclusions on the trends of the chatbot's metrics and make adjustments to the chatbot, using Excel.
- · Completed a research project to determine the validity of inferred personality scores using a NLP to interpret the validity over traditional structured interview.

Eagle Scout

Boy Scouts of America • May 2014 - March 2018

· Planned, managed, and executed a service project, in partnership with the local Children's Hospital, to improve the outdoor environment and expand the recreational areas for the facility.

COURSEWORK

Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning - Graduate Level

Auburn University • 2022 • Clustering, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Statistics, Data Collection

Coordinated on a software that would predict risk of earthquake in a specific area using clustering algorithms to evaluate risk. In Machine Learning, devised best methods of analyzing mood from self collected data using statistical learning models and data analysis.

SKILLS

Soft Skills: Customer Service, Management, Recruiting, Leadership, Communication, Agile Application Development. Hard Skills: Product Design, UX Design, Github, Database Design, .NET Framework, Payment Systems, App Development

Front End: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Back End: C#, Dart, Firebase Firestore, MSQL, Flutter